http://www.cftrust.org.uk/privacy-policy

We use cookies to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. By continuing to use our site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies. You can change your cookie settings at any time if you want. Find out more in our privacy and cookies policy.
Accept
Your donation will make a difference:
£15
£30
£50
Regular
One Off
Donate now
Helpline
Forum
I'd like to...
Learn about cross-infection
Learn about travel insurance
Learn about Trust research
Join a fundraising event
Become a corporate supporter
See answers to FAQs about cystic fibrosis
Get the latest news about cystic fibrosis
I am...
A parent of a newly diagnosed child
A person with cystic fibrosis
Close to someone with cystic fibrosis
Interested in donating
A fundraiser
A campaigner
A clinician
A teacher
Search
close
RegisterLogin
Life with CF
Life with CF
Find out what it means to live with cystic fibrosis.
Coronavirus
Updates and FAQs
Schools
Financial support and welfare advice
Your CF care
Government and clinical guidance
Mental and physical health
Cooking and shopping while shielding
CF Insight Survey
What is CF?
What is cystic fibrosis?
Find the answers to all of your questions about cystic fibrosis.
How is cystic fibrosis diagnosed?
Family genetic testing
The sweat test
How is cystic fibrosis treated?
Treatments and medication
Physiotherapy
Physiotherapy FAQs
Staying active
Activity library
CF Fitness Space
Diet
Transition
Why now?
Transition resources order form
What to expect
Your questions answered
Have a plan
Transplant information and resources
Cystic fibrosis and organ transplants
Personalised healthcare
Lets get personal
Five Feet Apart
What are the causes of cystic fibrosis?
FAQs
CF for teachers
Get involved
Get involved
Check out all of the ways you can get involved in our mission!
Donate money
Summer Raffle 2020
Lottery
Christmas Raffle
Not So Secret Santa
Christmas shop
Gifts in Wills
How to leave a gift in your Will
Life-saving drugs
Triple combination therapy (Kaftrio)
Campaign timeline
Life-saving drugs FAQs
Hope for more
Travel Fair
Clinical Trials Accelerator Platform
Participating centres
Trials Accelerator impact report
UK CF Registry
UK Cystic Fibrosis Conference
CF's Got Talent!
UKCFC 2017 video gallery
UKCFC 2018: day one
UKCFC 2018: day two
UKCFC 2018 video gallery
UKCFC 2019: day one
UKCFC 2019: day two
UKCFC 2019 video gallery
UK CFC 2016
Privacy Policy
At the Cystic Fibrosis Trust, we are committed to protecting your personal information and being transparent about what we do with it. We will use your personal information in accordance with all applicable laws concerning the protection of personal information and not to do anything with your information you wouldn’t reasonably expect.
This Privacy Policy covers:
Who are we
What the Cystic Fibrosis Trust’s privacy policy does
How we get your personal information
What information we collect
How we use your information
How we will communicate with you
What 'consent' and 'preferences' are
Who we share your information with
Children - anyone under the age of 16
Social media
Information & support services
Your rights
Cookies
Who are we?
In this policy references to the Cystic Fibrosis Trust, or Trust, or to ‘we’ or ‘us’ are to the Cystic Fibrosis Trust which is a registered charity in England and Wales 1079049, and in Scotland SC040196.
The Cystic Fibrosis Trust is what’s known as the ‘controller’ of the personal data you provide to us. We will usually collect basic personal data about you like your name, postal address, telephone number, email address and your bank details, if you are giving us a donation for example.
Sometimes we will collect other information about you such as your date of birth, gender, or your relationship to cystic fibrosis. We will always be very clear with you about the reasons why we may wish to collect such information, and we will only do so with your specific consent and permission.
Data Processors
Sometimes we appoint third parties to take on tasks for us like managing the production of print materials for delivery, including CF Life magazine, as well as the storage and delivery of fundraising materials such as running shirts. These third parties are known as 'data processors'.
Where we appoint a third party to process data, it will always be with a formal agreement in place between the Cystic Fibrosis Trust and that organisation, to protect the security of your data. See the full privacy policy for more on who we share your information with.
If you would like a list of third party processors you can request it by contacting:
Data Protection Officer
Cystic Fibrosis Trust
One Aldgate
Second Floor
London
EC3N 1RE
Email: dataprotectionofficer@cysticfibrosis.org.uk
Phone: 0203 795 2188
Regional Fundraising Volunteers
The Cystic Fibrosis Trust is supported by a network of fundraising volunteers, who carry out fundraising activity around the country on our behalf. These volunteers may collect personal data from members of the public who are involved with this fundraising activity. Because they are acting on our behalf, the Cystic Fibrosis Trust is the Data Controller for any personal data held by the volunteers, so the rest of this Privacy Policy also applies to that data.
What does the Trust’s privacy policy do?
Our privacy policy explains how we will use any data that you share with us. We are legally required to tell you how we will use this information and give you the opportunity to opt out of marketing communications (i.e. tell us not to use your information in that way). To make it easier to use and understand, our policy is set out as a series of frequently asked questions and answers that explain what information we gather, how we use it, where it goes and how you can find out more. If there’s anything you are unsure of, you can always contact our Supporter Care team on supportercare@cysticfibrosis.org.uk or 020 3795 2177 during regular office hours.
We may change this document from time to time to reflect the latest view of what we do with your information. Please check back frequently; you will be able to see if changes have been made by the date it was last updated at the end of the document
Read our full privacy policy
Research we fund
We fund research to tackle some of the most pressing issues in CF today. Find out how your donations are making a difference.
Take a look
What is CF?
Cystic fibrosis, or CF, affects the lungs, digestive system and other organs, and there are over 10,600 people living with it in the UK.
Find out more
Contact us
Get in touch with us to speak to someone on our Helpline, find out about an event or speak to our Press Team.
Get in touch
Share this page
